<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>John James, I hearing that thou doest make a noise up and down in the countrey amongst the ignorant ... here is a few queries for thee to answer in writing, and plainess of words ...</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1658</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 9 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40208</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1853B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R31685</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12244880</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12244880</idno>
            <idno type="VID">56912</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40208)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 56912)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1504:9)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>John James, I hearing that thou doest make a noise up and down in the countrey amongst the ignorant ... here is a few queries for thee to answer in writing, and plainess of words ...</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>4 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for M.W.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l.] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1658]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed on p. 4: G.F.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Date of publication suggested by Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Apologetic works.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:56912:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 4 -->
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:56912:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 4 -->
            <head>
               <hi>John James,</hi> I hearing that thou doeſt make a noiſe up and down in the Countrey amongſt the Ignorant, and hath ſpoken Reproachful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, and backbited the people of God, that by ſuch as thee are in ſcorn called <hi>Quakers,</hi> here is a few Queries for thee to anſwer in writing, and plaineſs of words, which if thou doſt not, we ſhall ſpread them abroad and ſet them in places where thou comes.</head>
            <p n="1">1. HAſt thou the ſame Spirit and Power as the Prophets and Apoſtles had.</p>
            <p n="2">2. Haſt thou the ſame Revelation and Inſpiration, and Spirit of Prophecy, and pouring forth of the Holy Ghoſt, and doeſt thon own the pouring forth of the ſpirit upon Sons and Daughters, and is not this the laſt time, in which it ſhould be poured out, and the Sons and Daughters ſhould Propheſie, and Old men dream Dreams, and Young men ſee Viſions;</p>
            <p n="3">3. Haſt thou heard Gods voice, and Chriſts voice immediately from Heaven, or art thou one of them the Lord never ſent, nor ſpake unto, Anſwer me theſe Queries.</p>
            <p n="4">4. Doeſt thou own that Chriſt that dyed at <hi>Ieruſalens</hi> to be the Light that Enlighteneth every man that comes into the World, and are not all Enlightened by him either to their Salvation or condemnation.</p>
            <p n="5">5. What and where is that which muſt give the knowledge of God, is it within people or without the, Aſwer me according to plain Scripture.</p>
            <p n="6">6. Doeſt thou preach, that whileſt a man is upon the Earth, he may be freed from ſin, and the body of death, and Imperfecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and ſhall be perfect whileſt he be upon Earth; or doſt thou keep people in the ſtate of thy Father <hi>Adam</hi> and Mother <hi>Eve</hi> in the Fall, or doſt thou bring them to the ſtate before they fell, and ſo to Chriſt that ſhall never fall, which of theſe ſtates doeſt thou bring them to, and keep thy flock in, in <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> in the fall, or <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> before they fell, or in Chriſt that ſhall never fall, thou muſt keep thy Flock in one of theſe three ſtates, and which of them is it, haſt thou brought any of thy Flock whom thou driveſt to that Condition and ſtate, they need no man teach them, that is to the anointing in them, the Law in their hearts, whereby they need not ſay to one another know the Lord, and
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:56912:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 5 -->
that is to the light of Chriſt that ſhines in their hearts to give them the Light of the knowledge of the glory of God in the face of Chriſt Jeſus, and how many haſt thou brought hither.</p>
            <p n="7">7. What is the Mother of Harlots, and what is the Beaſt ſhe rides upon, and what are the Peoples, Nations, and Multitudes; and Tongues the Whore ſits upon, and what is Myſterie <hi>Babylon,</hi> and what is the Woman that went into the Wilderneſs, and what was her time ſhe was to be there, and what is the Beaſts and Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gons worſhip, and what is a will VVorſhip, and what is it to worſhip Angels, and what is that which leads Nature into its Courſe, and ſo to the glory of the firſt body, and what is the glo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of the ſecond body, and what is that which leads Nature out of its Courſe, and ſo ſets the whole Courſe of Nature on Fire.</p>
            <p n="8">8. VVhat is the ground of that which keeps in good manners, and what is that which corrupts them, and what is the Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs the world is reproved of, and what is the Judgements, and what is that which lead the Saints into all truth, and hath every one the Spirit of God, and whether bowing, bending, doffing hats, ſcraping, cringing, ſaying you to one', be the honour that comes from above, or what is it, and whence comes it, and whether this before mentioned to not ſtand in that Nature, part and prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciple which is on fire, if it hath not theſe things, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore whether or noe theſe things do proceed from that which leads Nature into its Courſe, or out of its Courſe, and what is it that defaces the glory of the firſt body.</p>
            <p n="9">9. VVhether or no doeſt thou own Trembling and Quaking at the word of God.</p>
            <p n="10">10. Seeing thou looks upon thy ſelf to differ from the world, and to be above them, let us ſee wherein, and in what it is ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſt.</p>
            <p n="11">11. VVhat is ſelf-Righteouſneſs, and what is mans Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and the Righteouſneſs that is as filthy Rags, diſtinguiſh theſe one from another, or whether they be all one, for our Righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſs is that which was before <hi>Adam</hi> was, whom ye in ſcorn calls Quakers.</p>
            <p n="12">12. VVhether ever thou came to ſee ſo far as <hi>Balaams</hi> Aſſe, that is to ſay, to ſee the Angel of the Lord.</p>
            <p n="13">
               <pb n="3" facs="tcp:56912:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 5 -->
13. What are the Graves, and the Tombs, and the Sepulchres, and the fowls of the Aire, and the neſts they ſit in, which Chriſt ſpake of, Anſwer.</p>
            <p n="14">14. VVhether or no to pay Tyths or receive Tyths is not to deny Chriſt Jeſus to be come in the fleſh, and to deny Chriſt to be offered up, the offering once for all, and was not their of the Tyths a heave Offring, and was not that Offering to be ended by Chriſt offering up himſelf, and had not the Preiſts a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandment to take Tyths of the people, of their brethren, and do not you tranſgreſs the Law of God which takes them of thoſe you do not call brethren, and was not the widdows, fatherleſse and ſtrangers to have a part of the Tyths, and was every Preiſt and Levit, and them that was to have a part of them, to have a particular Tyth Barn, and was Tyths to be ſould, and was their a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Impropriators, and whether they do not hold up the Preiſts of the Jews, and their Law and Commandments that take Tyths and give Tyths and ſo denys Chriſt the Preiſt, in holding up the Jews Preiſts.</p>
            <p n="15">15. And whether or no <hi>Melchiſedeck</hi> did take Tyths of all other Nations that were under him, or any other ſpoile but once of <hi>Abraham,</hi> and whether he had a command for doing it, or whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther it was an Example.</p>
            <p n="16">16. Whether the Jews did take Tyths of the <hi>Cananites</hi> or any of thoſe Nations that lived amougſt them, or of any people where ever they came that they had the power over, that was not of them.</p>
            <p n="17">17. You that ſpeaks ſo much of Chriſt Reigning, whether or no <hi>Your Swords are bear into Plowſhares, and your Speares into Pru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning books, that you do not learn War any more; that Nation ſhall not life up a Sword againſt Nation;</hi> And whether or no this Miniſtration ſhould be amongſt Chriſtians, ſeeing that it was Chriſts Doctrine, <hi>That they ſhould love one onother and love Enemies,</hi> and he bid <hi>Peter put up his ſword,</hi> and the Apoſtle ſaid <hi>their Weapons were ſpiritual:</hi> Secondly, Doth not <hi>Peter</hi> ſay <hi>That the Heavens muſt receive Chriſt Ieſus until the time of Reſtitution of all things, which God hath ſpoken by the mouth of his Prophets ſince the World began,</hi> Acts 3. Now do you look at reſtoring of things, then by what doth Chriſt reſtore, whether by his Light and power within people or with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:56912:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 6 -->
them, ſeeing the ſin is within them, and whether or no Chriſt doth not remain in the Heavens until all things be reſtored, and whether or no Chriſt do not now Reign, and whether or no he is not reſtoring, and then by what (as I ſaid before) doth he re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtore ſeeing he is in the Heavens, and muſt remaine in the Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vens until all things be reſtored, and whether or no ſome was not reſtored, when they ſate in the Heavenly places in Chriſt Jeſus, <hi>Eph.</hi> 2. And whether or no he that remaines in the Heavens, be not alſo manifeſt in man, that is reſtored, and lives, and walks, and Reigns in him; Anſwer this thou that talks of a perſonal Reigne.</p>
            <p>And Anſwer theſe Queries to the ſame thing queried, in writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, if thou be a Miniſter of Chriſt, as thou haſt ſo publiſhed thy ſelf, if not it will manifeſt whether thou be not one of the dumb, Sheapheards ſpoken of in <hi>Iſa. And in thy ſilence it will make thee manifest to be one of the evil beaſts whoſe mouth is ſtopt.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>If thou do not give us thy Anſwer within two weeks, we may cauſe this to be Printed, becauſe thou haſt ſlan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derouſly reported of us.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G. F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed for <hi>M.W.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb facs="tcp:56912:3"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 6 -->
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
